<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE operator SYSTEM "ophidiaoperator.dtd">
<operator name="OPH_INTERCUBE" version="1.0">
    <info>
        <abstract>[Type]
Data Process.

[Behaviour]
It executes an operation between two datacubes with the same fragmentation structure and
returns a new datacube as result of the specified operation applied element by element.

[Parameters]
- cube : name of the first operand datacube. The name must be in PID format.
         Considered only in case 'cubes' is not set.
- cube2 : name of the second operand datacube. The name must be in PID format.
          Considered only in case 'cubes' is not set.
- cubes : list of input cubes (only two are significant). The name must be in PID format.
          If set, the parameters 'cube' and 'cube2' are not considered.
- operation : type of inter-cube operation among these (default is sub):
              -- sum : sum correspondent elements one by one;
              -- sub : subtract the elements of the second operand from the first operand one by one (default);
              -- mul : multiply correspondent elements one by one;
              -- div : divide the elements of the first operand by the elements of the second operand one by one;
              -- abs : compute the modulus of corresponding elements one by one;
              -- arg : compute the phase of corresponding elements one by one;
              -- corr: compute the Pearson correlation coefficient row by row;
              -- mask: take all elements of cube corresponding to 1s in cube2,
                    remaining elements are set to 0 (int, byte, short or long) or NaN (float or double);
              -- max: return the maximum value between the corresponding elements one by one;
              -- min: return the minimum value between the corresponding elements one by one;
              -- arg_max: return 1 if the maximum value is associated with the first cube, 2 otherwise;
              -- arg_min: return 1 if the minimum value is associated with the first cube, 2 otherwise.
- missingvalue : value to be considered as missing value; by default it is NAN (for float and double).
- measure : name of the new measure resulting from the specified operation
- schedule : scheduling algorithm. The only possible value is 0,
		     for a static linear block distribution of resources.
- container : name of the container to be used to store the output cube; by default it is the container of the first cube.
- description : additional description to be associated with the output cube.
        
[System parameters]    
- exec_mode : operator execution mode. Possible values are async (default) for
              asynchronous mode, sync for synchronous mode with json-compliant output.
- ncores : number of parallel processes to be used (min. 1).
- sessionid : session identifier used server-side to manage sessions and jobs.
              Usually users don't need to use/modify it, except when it is necessary
              to create a new session or switch to another one.
- objkey_filter : filter on the output of the operator written to file (default=all => no filter, none => no output).
                  intercube : show operator's output PID as text.
        
[Examples]       
Sum the datacubes identified by the PIDs &quot;http://www.example.com/1/1&quot; and &quot;http://www.example.com/1/2&quot; :
OPH_TERM: oph_intercube cube=http://www.example.com/1/1;cube2=http://www.example.com/1/2;operation=sum;output_measure=new_pressure;
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_intercube;cube=http://www.example.com/1/1;cube2=http://www.example.com/1/2;operation=sum;output_measure=new_pressure;&quot;</abstract>
        <author>CMCC Foundation</author>
        <category>Data Analysis</category>
        <creationdate>12/05/2014</creationdate>
        <license url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt">GPLv3</license>
        <permission>write</permission>
    </info>
    <args>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">sessionid</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="1">ncores</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="async" values="async|sync">exec_mode</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" multivalue="yes" default="-">cube</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">cube2</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" multivalue="yes" default="-">cubes</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="sub" values="sum|sub|mul|div|abs|arg|corr|mask|max|min|arg_max|arg_min">operation</argument>
		<argument type="real" mandatory="no" default="NAN">missingvalue</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">measure</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="0" values="0">schedule</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">container</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">description</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all" values="all|none|intercube">objkey_filter</argument>
    </args>
</operator>
