<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE operator SYSTEM "ophidiaoperator.dtd">
<operator name="OPH_RESUME" version="1.0">
    <info>
        <abstract>[Type]
Data and Metadata Access

[Behaviour]
Request the list of the commands submitted within a session or the output of a command.

[Parameters]
- session       : identifier of the intended session, by default it is the working session.
- id            : identifier of the intended workflow or marker, by default no filter is applied.
- id_type       : use &quot;workflow&quot; (default) or &quot;marker&quot; to set the filter &quot;id&quot;.
- document_type : document type, &quot;request&quot; or &quot;response&quot;.
- level         : use level &quot;0&quot; to ask for submitted commands (short version) or workflow progress ratio;
                  use level &quot;1&quot; to ask for submitted commands (short version) or workflow output (default);
                  use level &quot;2&quot; to ask for submitted commands (extended version) or the list of workflow tasks;
                  use level &quot;3&quot; to ask for JSON Requests or the list of workflow task outputs;
                  use level &quot;4&quot; to ask for the list of commands associated to tasks of a workflow (valid only for a specific workflow);
                  use level &quot;5&quot; to ask for original JSON Request (valid only for a specific workflow).
- user          : filter by name of the submitter, by default no filter is applied; valid only for workflow list (&quot;id&quot;=0).
- status_filter : in case of running workflows, filter by job status according to the following bitmaps:
		- 1xxxxxxx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_PENDING
		- x1xxxxxx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_WAITING
		- xx1xxxxx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_RUNNING (or similar)
		- xxx1xxxx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_COMPLETED
		- xxxx1xxx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_ERROR (or similar)
		- xxxxx1xx : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_SKIPPED (due to errors)
		- xxxxxx1x : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_ABORTED
		- xxxxxxx1 : return references to jobs whose status is OPH_STATUS_UNSELECTED
		- 11111111 : default bitmap.
- execute : in case the command is used to retrieve the request for a specified workflow or a sub-workflow associated with a checkpoint,
            set this parameter to &quot;yes&quot; to execute it.
- checkpoint: in case the command is used to retrieve the request for a specified workflow,
              use this parameter to refer to the sub-workflow associated with a checkpoint as follows:
              - set it to &quot;all&quot; to retrieve the workflow with al the tasks (default);
              - set it to &quot;last&quot; to retrieve the sub-workflow associated with the last checkpoint passed successfully;
              - set it to the value of a checkpoint to the sub-workflow associated with the checkpoint if passed successfully.

[System parameters]
- sessionid : session identifier used server-side to manage sessions and jobs.
              Usually users don't need to use/modify it, except when it is necessary
              to create a new session or switch to another one.
- objkey_filter : filter on the output of the operator written to file (default=all => no filter, none => no output).
                  resume : show output.
- save : used to save session identifier on server.

[Examples]
Get the list of the commands submmitted within the working session:
OPH_TERM: oph_resume
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_resume;&quot;
Get the first command of the working session:
OPH_TERM: oph_resume id=1;
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_resume;id=1;&quot;</abstract>
        <author>CMCC Foundation</author>
        <category>Administration</category>
        <creationdate>11/07/2014</creationdate>
        <license url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt">GPLv3</license>
        <permission>read</permission>
    </info>
    <args>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="this">session</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="0" minvalue="0">id</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="workflow" values="workflow|marker">id_type</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="response" values="request|response">document_type</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="0" maxvalue="5" values="0|1|2|3|4|5">level</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="">user</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="11111111">status_filter</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="no" values="yes|no">save</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="no" values="yes|no">execute</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all">checkpoint</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">sessionid</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all" values="all|none|resume">objkey_filter</argument>
    </args>
</operator>
