<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE operator SYSTEM "ophidiaoperator.dtd">
<operator name="OPH_MERGECUBES2" version="1.0">
    <info>
        <abstract>[Type]
Data Process.

[Behaviour]
It merges the measures of n input datacubes with the same fragmentation structure and
creates a new datacube with the union of the n measures. NOTE: only single measure 
data cubes can be merged. A new implicit dimension will be created.

[Parameters]
- cubes : name of the datacubes to merge. The names must be in PID format.
          Multiple-value field: list of cubes separated by &quot;|&quot; can be provided.
- schedule : scheduling algorithm. The only possible value is 0, for a static linear block distribution of resources.
- container : name of the container to be used to store the output cube; by default it is the input container.
- dim : name of the new dimension to be created; by default a unique random name is chosen.
- dim_type: data type associated with the new dimension. Default value is &quot;long&quot;.
- number : number of replies of the first cube; by default the first cube is considered only once.
- description : additional description to be associated with the output cube.
- order : criteria on which input cubes are ordered before merging:
          - source : cubes are ordered by source, provided that level is 0
          By default input cubes are not ordered.
        
[System parameters]    
- exec_mode : operator execution mode. Possible values are async (default) for
              asynchronous mode, sync for synchronous mode with json-compliant output.
- ncores : number of parallel processes to be used (min. 1).
- sessionid : session identifier used server-side to manage sessions and jobs.
              Usually users don't need to use/modify it, except when it is necessary
              to create a new session or switch to another one.
- objkey_filter : filter on the output of the operator written to file (default=all => no filter, none => no output).
                  mergecubes : show operator's output PID as text.
        
[Examples]       
Merge the datacubes identified by the PIDs &quot;http://www.example.com/1/1&quot; and &quot;http://www.example.com/1/2&quot; :
OPH_TERM: oph_mergecubes2 cubes=http://www.example.com/1/1|http://www.example.com/1/2;
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_mergecubes2;cubes=http://www.example.com/1/1|http://www.example.com/1/2;&quot;</abstract>
        <author>CMCC Foundation</author>
        <category>Data Analysis</category>
        <creationdate>27/07/2013</creationdate>
        <license url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt">GPLv3</license>
        <permission>write</permission>
    </info>
    <args>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">sessionid</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="1">ncores</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="async" values="async|sync">exec_mode</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="yes" multivalue="yes">cubes</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="0" values="0">schedule</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">container</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">dim</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="long" values="double|float|int|long|short|byte">dim_type</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="1">number</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">description</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="none" values="none|source">order</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all" values="all|none|mergecubes">objkey_filter</argument>
    </args>
</operator>
