<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE operator SYSTEM "ophidiaoperator.dtd">
<operator name="OPH_B2DROP" version="1.0">
    <info>
        <abstract>[Type]
Data Access.

[Behaviour]
It uploads/downloads a file onto/from a B2DROP remote folder. Note that in order to be able to use the operator, a netrc file with the credentials to B2DROP is required. Commonly the hidden .netrc file resides in the user's home directory.

[Parameters]
- action: it allows to specify if the file provided in src_path has to be downloaded
		   - with get - or uploaded (default) - with put - from/to B2DROP.  
- auth_path: absolute path to the netrc file containing the B2DROP login information. 
			 Note that it is not possible to use double dots (..) within the path. 
			 If no path is provided, the user's home will be used (default).
- src_path: when the action to be performed is "put" it specifies the path to the file 
			to be uploaded to B2DROP. The path can be absolute or relative. 
			In case of relative path the cdd argument will be pre-pended (default). 
			Otherwise when the action to be performed is "get" it specifies the path 
			of the file on B2DROP. In case no path is specified, the base path will 
			be used (default).
			Note that it is not possible to use double dots (..) within the path.
- dst_path: when the action to be performed is "put" it provides the path where the file 
			will be uploaded on B2DROP. In case no path is specified, the base path and 
			the input file name will be used (default).
			Otherwise when the action to be performed is "get" it provides the path where
			the file from B2DROP is going to be downloaded. The path can be absolute 
			or relative. In case of relative path the cdd argument will be pre-pended.
			In case no path is specified, the cdd and the input file name will be 
			used (default). WARNING: If the path specified refers to an existing file, 
			this will be overwritten.
			Note that it is not possible to use double dots (..) within the path.
- cdd : absolute path corresponding to the current directory on data repository.

[System parameters]
- exec_mode : operator execution mode. Possible values are async (default) for
              asynchronous mode, sync for synchronous mode with json-compliant output.
- ncores : number of parallel processes to be used (min. 1).
           This operator is not parallel, so the only possible value is 1.
- sessionid : session identifier used server-side to manage sessions and jobs.
              Usually users don't need to use/modify it, except when it is necessary
              to create a new session or switch to another one.
- objkey_filter : filter on the output of the operator written to file (default=all => no filter, none => no output).
                  b2drop : show operator's output.

[Examples]
Upload the file &quot;test.nc&quot; into B2DROP base folder:
OPH_TERM: oph_b2drop src_path=test.nc;
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_b2drop;src_path=test.nc;&quot;</abstract>
        <author>CMCC Foundation</author>
        <category>Miscellaneous</category>
        <creationdate>12/07/2018</creationdate>
        <license url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt">GPLv3</license>
        <permission>execute</permission>
    </info>
    <args>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="put" values="get|put">action</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">auth_path</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="yes" multivalue="yes">src_path</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="-">dst_path</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="/">cdd</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="async" values="async|sync">exec_mode</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">sessionid</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="1" maxvalue="1">ncores</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all" values="all|none|b2drop">objkey_filter</argument>
    </args>
</operator>
