<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE operator SYSTEM "ophidiaoperator.dtd">
<operator name="OPH_EXPORTNC" version="1.0">
    <info>
        <abstract>[Type]
Data Process.

[Behaviour]
It exports data of a datacube into multiple NetCDF files.

[Parameters]
- cube : name of the input datacube. The name must be in PID format.
- schedule : scheduling algorithm. The only possible value is 0,
             for a static linear block distribution of resources.
- misc : if &quot;yes&quot; data are saved in session folder called &quot;export/misc&quot;;
         if &quot;no&quot; data are saved within &quot;export/nc&quot; in a subfolder associated with the PID of the cube (default).
- output_path : absolute path of the NetCDF output files. In case of default value, all files will be saved in the appropriate
                directory corresponding to the related container and cube in the nc folder at the framework installation directory.
                In case it is set to &quot;local&quot;, the file will be saved in current directory on data repository (see &quot;cdd&quot;).
- output_name : filename of the NetCDF output files. In case of multiple fragments, filenames will be &quot;output_name0.nc&quot;, &quot;output_name1.nc&quot;, etc.
                The default value is the measure name of input datacube.
- output : alias for the pair &quot;output_path&quot; and &quot;output_name&quot;; the values of these arguments will be overwritten.
- cdd : absolute path corresponding to the current directory on data repository.
- force : flag used to force file creation. An existant file is overwritten with &quot;yes&quot; whereas
          the file is created only if it does not exist with &quot;no&quot; (default).
- export_metadata: imports also metadata with &quot;yes&quot; (default)
                   or only data with &quot;no&quot;.

[System parameters]    
- exec_mode : operator execution mode. Possible values are async (default) for
              asynchronous mode, sync for synchronous mode with json-compliant output.
- ncores : number of parallel processes to be used (min. 1).
- sessionid : session identifier used server-side to manage sessions and jobs.
              Usually users don't need to use/modify it, except when it is necessary
              to create a new session or switch to another one.
- objkey_filter : filter on the output of the operator written to file (default=all => no filter, none => no output).
		exportnc : no output.
        
[Examples] 
Export data of the datacube identified by the PID &quot;http://www.example.com/1/1&quot; :
OPH_TERM: oph_exportnc cube=http://www.example.com/1/1;
SUBMISSION STRING: &quot;operator=oph_exportnc;cube=http://www.example.com/1/1;&quot;</abstract>
        <author>CMCC Foundation</author>
        <category>Data Import/Export</category>
        <creationdate>27/07/2013</creationdate>
        <license url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt">GPLv3</license>
        <permission>write</permission>
    </info>
    <args>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="yes" multivalue="yes">cube</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="no" values="yes|no">misc</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="default">output_path</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="default">output_name</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="">output</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="/">cdd</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="no" values="yes|no">force</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="yes" values="yes|no">export_metadata</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="0" values="0">schedule</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="async" values="async|sync">exec_mode</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="null">sessionid</argument>
		<argument type="int" mandatory="no" default="1" minvalue="1">ncores</argument>
		<argument type="string" mandatory="no" default="all" values="all|none|exportnc">objkey_filter</argument>
    </args>
</operator>
